A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, Officers' Diaries xFA118
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Gunn, Selskar M.
  - 1929 (Reel M Gun 1, Frame 730, Box 187)
    This diary details Selskar Gunn's interviews and correspondence between January 2, 1929 and December 27, 1929 with various senior staff and field directors from the RF's IHD program in Europe, medical officers seeking fellowships from the IHD, and reports from those individuals on Public Health progress in Europe. This diary contains mostly recordings of correspondence and meetings but also records Gunn's travels to Spain, England, Switzerland, Hungary, and the Kingdom of Jugoslavia during this period. During these visits, Gunn met with local public health officials and Rockefeller Foundation associates to discuss the progress of public health work and medical education in these nations, as well as being granted a private audience with the Queen of Jugoslavia. The movements of various senior staff and field directors on their own trips and inspection tours throughout Europe are also recorded for this period.
    Diaries; Europe; Public health; Sanitation; Medical sciences; Medical education; Rockefeller Foundation; Gunn, Selskar Michael
  - Index, 1930 (Reel M Gun 1, Frame 900, Box 187)
    Index to "Diary: 1930." Nine pages.
    indexes (reference sources); Gunn, Selskar Michael; Rockefeller Foundation
  - 1930 (Reel M Gun 1, Frame 909, Box 187)
    This diary details Mr. Gunn's correspondence between January 2, 1930 to October 1, 1930 with various senior staff and field directors from the RF's IHD program in Europe, medical officers seeking fellowships from the IHD, and reports from those individuals on Public Health progress in Europe. Further, Gunn's business trips to London, Rome, Belgrade, Budapest, Prague, and Berlin to meet with various field directors of the RF and local public health authorities is recorded as well. Gunn also reports on the travels of staff officers and associates around the continent on behalf of the RF. The last section of Gunn's diary is an extended memoranda which recounts the conversations and resolutions made in London between Gunn and administrators at several English universities about the state and progress of various projects on the African continent.
    Diaries; Medical sciences; Public health; Medical education; Europe; Sanitation; Rockefeller Foundation; Gunn, Selskar Michael
  - Index, 1931 (Reel M Gun 1, Frame 1,032, Box 187)
    Index to "Diary: 1931." Two pages.
  - 1931 (Box 187, Reel M Gun 1, Frame 1,035)
    This diary details Mr. Gunn's correspondence from 2 January, 1931 to 5 March, 1931. It is primarily composed of memoranda of meetings between Mr. Gunn and the directors and professors of the London School of Economics, the International Institute for African Languages and Cultures, and the National Institute of Industrial Psychology. The memoranda exhibit the RF's efforts to expand social science research and education in the European community with the cooperation and collaboration of local resources. It also contains records of correspondence with RF senior staff and IHD European Field Directors.
    Medical sciences; Public health; Medical education; Europe; Sanitation; Diaries; Rockefeller Foundation; Gunn, Selskar Michael
  - Table of Contents, 1932-1933 (Box 187, Reel M Gun 1, Frame 1,061)
    Table of Contents to "Diary: 1932-1933." One page.
    Gunn, Selskar Michael; Rockefeller Foundation
  - 1932-1933 (Box 187, Reel M Gun 1, Frame 1,063)
    This diary is a record of Mr. Gunn's interviews and travels between October 21, 1932 and September 11, 1933. This first part of Gunn's diary is devoted to his time in Hawaii interviewing the professors, doctors, and administrators of the University of Hawaii and various public health institutes. While Gunn's diary states he sailed for Yokohama Japan on Oct. 28th, the next entry on Nov. 28th places him in present-day Beijing at Yenching University. The rest of the diary records Gunn's travels to the major cities in China, inspecting the universities receiving funding from the RF and recording the state of Chinese education. Two particularly long entries record the poor quality of academic discipline in the Chinese university and the current and growing state of the hostilities between KMT and Communist forces in Fukien province.
    Japan; Sanitation; Hawaii; Diaries; China; Medical sciences; Public health; Medical education; Gunn, Selskar Michael; Rockefeller Foundation
- Hackett, Lewis W.
  - Index, 1940 (Box 188, Reel M Hac 1, Frame 1)
    1940 Index; Index of Persons and Institutions, 4 pages.
    indexes (reference sources); Brazil; Argentina; South America; Hackett, Lewis Wendell; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division
  - Index, 1941 (Box 188, Reel M Hac 1, Frame 5)
    1941 Index; Index of Persons, Institutions and Diseases, 10 pages.
    Public health; South America; Medicine -- Research; indexes (reference sources); Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Hackett, Lewis Wendell
  - Index, 1942 (Box 188, Reel M Hac 1, Frame 15)
    1942 Index; Index of Persons, Institutions and Diseases, 10 pages.
    South America; Medicine -- Research; Public health; Yellow fever; indexes (reference sources); Malaria; Tuberculosis; Typhoid fever; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Hackett, Lewis Wendell
  - Index, 1943 (Reel M Hac 1, Frame 25, Box 188)
    1943 Index; Index of Persons, Institutions and Diseases, 5 pages.
    indexes (reference sources); Malaria; Hookworm disease; Yellow fever; Public health; South America; Medical education; Medicine -- Research; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Hackett, Lewis Wendell
  - Index, 1944 (Box 188, Reel M Hac 1, Frame 30)
    1944 Index; Index of Persons, Institutions and Diseases, 11 pages.
    indexes (reference sources); Hackett, Lewis Wendell; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division
  - Index, 1945 (Box 188, Reel M Hac 1, Frame 41)
    1945 Index; Index of Persons, Institutions and Diseases, 9 pages.
  - Index, 1946 (Box 188, Reel M Hac 1, Frame 50)
    1946 Index; alphabetical index, 8 pages.
  - Index, 1947 (Reel M Hac 1, Frame 58, Box 188)
    1947 Index; alphabetical index, 11 pages.
  - Index, 1948 (Reel M Hac 1, Frame 69, Box 188)
    1948 Index; alphabetical index, 9 pages.
  - Index, 1949 (Reel M Hac 1, Frame 78, Box 188)
    1949 Index; alphabetical index to diary January 1-September 14, 1949, 9 pages.
    indexes (reference sources); Hackett, Lewis Wendell; Rockefeller Foundation
  - 1940 (Reel M Hac 1, Frame 87, Box 188)
    As an Assistant Director to the International Health Division, Hackett's diary is arranged according to interview and visit. He holds interviews, conferences, and visits with professionals in the field of medical research. Hackett surveys various medical institutions, laboratories and public health facilities in South America to assess their response to various tropical diseases. He keeps statistics and notes on the various diseases on how they affect the localities.
    Medicine -- Research; Yellow fever; South America; Argentina; Malaria; Public health; Diaries; Brazil; Hackett, Lewis Wendell; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division
  - 1941 (Box 188, Reel M Hac 1, Frame 180)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Hackett discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of public health. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. Hackett assess various tropical diseases in South America and the local response to these outbreaks. He surveys and tours various health facilities, laboratories and medical schools.
    Chile; South America; Diaries; Malaria; Hookworm disease; Trinidad; Public health; Medicine -- Research; Yellow fever; Bolivia; Peru; Ecuador; Uruguay; Hackett, Lewis Wendell; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division
  - 1942 (Box 188, Reel M Hac 1, Frame 513)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Hackett discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of public health. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. Hackett assess various tropical diseases in South America and the local response to these outbreaks. He surveys and tours various health facilities, laboratories and medical schools. The diary includes photographs.
    Diaries; Tuberculosis; Typhoid fever; Yellow fever; Malaria; Medicine -- Research; Public health; Bolivia; Peru; Uruguay; Paraguay; South America; Argentina; Hackett, Lewis Wendell; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division
  - 1943 (Box 188, Reel M Hac 1, Frame 778)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Hackett discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of public health. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. Hackett assess various tropical diseases in South America and the local response to these outbreaks. He surveys and tours various health facilities, laboratories and medical schools. The diary details the Argentina program and progress on construction. Includes hand drawn map.
    Malaria; Hookworm disease; Diaries; Medical education; Medicine -- Research; Public health; Chile; Argentina; Peru; Ecuador; South America; Yellow fever; Hackett, Lewis Wendell; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division
  - 1944 (Box 188, Reel M Hac 2, Frame 1)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Hackett discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of public health. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. Hackett assess various tropical diseases in South America and the local response to these outbreaks. He surveys and tours various health facilities, laboratories and medical schools. Hackett continues to assist in the creation of local South American public health infrastructure. Included also are updates and excerpts from RF staff member diaries.
    Colombia; Mexico; Guatemala; Bolivia; Diaries; United States; Uruguay; Ecuador; Argentina; Hackett, Lewis Wendell; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division
  - 1945 (Box 189, Reel M Hac 2, Frame 302)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Hackett discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of public health. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. Hackett assess various tropical diseases in South America and the local response to these outbreaks. He surveys and tours various health facilities, laboratories and medical schools. Hackett continues to assist in the creation of local South American public health infrastructure. The diary describes the current Argentinean political situation as well as the Revolution of 1943 and the after effects. The Chilean program is outlined.
    Diaries; Hookworm disease; Typhus fever; Smallpox; Malaria; Typhoid fever; Yellow fever; United States; DDT (Insecticide); Hygiene; Public health nursing; Nutrition; Uruguay; Argentina; Peru; Chile; Colombia; Bolivia; Public health; South America; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Hackett, Lewis Wendell
  - 1946 (Box 189, Reel M Hac 2, Frame 584)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Hackett discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of public health. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. Hackett assess various tropical diseases in South America and the local response to these outbreaks. He surveys and tours various health facilities, laboratories and medical schools. Hackett continues to assist in the creation of local South American public health infrastructure. The diary documents the day to day build up to revolution, civil war and political strife in South America. The diary includes photographs and extracts of staff member diaries.
    Diaries; Trinidad; Dominican Republic; United States; Ecuador; South America; Public health; DDT (Insecticide); Hygiene; Argentina; Yellow fever; Malaria; Hookworm disease; Brazil; Peru; Bolivia; Chile; Medicine -- Research; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Hackett, Lewis Wendell
  - 1947 (Box 189, Reel M Hac 3, Frame 1)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Hackett discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of public health. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. Hackett assess various tropical diseases in South America and the local response to these outbreaks. He surveys and tours various health facilities, laboratories and medical schools. Hackett continues to assist in the creation of local South American public health infrastructure. The diary details the IHD projects in Mexico such as the Vera Cruz studies. The DDT programs for South America are outlined. Communicable Disease Programs are documented. Updates from staff member diaries are included as well as photographs. Hackett attended the Meeting of the Directing Council of the Pan-American Sanitary Organization in Buenos Aires, Sept. 24-Oct. 2, 1947, and the 16th National Congress of Hygiene in Brazil.
    United States; Mexico; Malaria; Typhus fever; Peru; Chile; Panama; Venezuela; Communicable diseases; DDT (Insecticide); Sanitation; Cholera; Hygiene; Yellow fever; Smallpox; Hookworm disease; Diaries; Public health; South America; Brazil; Argentina; Medical education; Medicine -- Research; Public health nursing; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Hackett, Lewis Wendell
  - 1948 (Box 189, Reel M Hac 3, Frame 280)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Hackett discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of public health. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. Hackett assess various tropical diseases in South America and the local response to these outbreaks. He surveys and tours various health facilities, laboratories and medical schools. Hackett continues to assist in the creation of local South American public health infrastructure. The diary documents civil and political unrest in South America, updates from staff member diaries, and outlines various DDT programs. Hackett attended the UNESCO conference, the APHA meeting and an IHD Regional Staff Conference. Included in this diary are photographs and a hand drawn map of Bolivia entitled "Areas to be Covered by the Division of Epidemiology and Control of Rural Endemic Diseases."
    Smallpox; Syphilis; Typhus fever; Medicine -- Research; Diaries; Medical education; Malaria; Hygiene; South America; Ecuador; Public health nursing; Public health; Peru; Uruguay; Brazil; United States; Yellow fever; Plague; Argentina; DDT (Insecticide); Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Hackett, Lewis Wendell
  - 1949 (Box 190, Reel M Hac 3, Frame 575)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Hackett discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of public health. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. Hackett assess various tropical diseases in South America and the local response to these outbreaks. He surveys and tours various health facilities, laboratories and medical schools. Hackett continues to assist in the creation of local South American public health infrastructure. Hackett attends Interdivisional Conference on Population Problems, and an APHA meeting. Documentation on the DDT experiments is included as well. Includes photographs, a map entitled, "Plague Regions in Bolivia", a map entitled, "Bolivia Distribution of Malaria."
    Hookworm disease; Nutrition; Plague; Malaria; Typhus fever; Yellow fever; Smallpox; Communicable diseases; Diaries; Leprosy; Argentina; Sanitation; Syphilis; DDT (Insecticide); Uruguay; Peru; Ecuador; Chile; United States; Ireland; England; France; Public health; Public health nursing; Medical education; Medicine -- Research; Tuberculosis; Hepatits; Population; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Hackett, Lewis Wendell
  - 1950 (Box 190, Reel M Hac 3, Frame 892)
    A brief 10 page diary with notes on the Sardinian Malaria campaign.
    Medicine -- Research; Public health; Malaria; Diaries; Italy; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Hackett, Lewis Wendell
- Haddow, Alexander J.
  - 1942-1950 (Box 191)
- Hahn, Richard G.
  - 1939-1952 (Box 191)
- Hansens, Elton J.
  - 1943 (Box 191)
- Hanson, Frank B.
  - 1930-1931 (Box 192, Reel M Han 1, Frame 1)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Hanson, professionals and students in the field of natural sciences. The diary details his tours of various laboratories, discussions of research and impressions of fellowship applicants. Included is an index by place titled "Contents."
    Diaries; Zoology; Bulgaria; Botany; Greece; Physics; Italy; France; Denmark; Netherlands; Wales; Sweden; Ireland; Latvia; Chemistry; Biology -- Research; Russia; Europe; Germany; Switzerland; Poland; Austria; Hanson, Frank B.; Rockefeller Foundation
  - 1932 (Box 192, Reel M Han 1, Frame 276)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Hanson, professionals and students in the field of natural sciences. Entries record his tours of various laboratories, discussions of research and impressions of fellowship applicants.
    Hungary; Diaries; Sweden; Finland; Russia; Netherlands; Switzerland; Germany; Physics; Botany; Zoology; Biology -- Research; Chemistry; Europe; Hanson, Frank B.; Rockefeller Foundation
  - 1933 September 4-December 26 (Reel M Han 1, Frame 459, Box 192)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Hanson, professionals and students in the field of natural sciences. Entries record his tours of various laboratories, discussions of research and impressions of fellowship applicants. Hanson is now an Assistant Director of the RF Natural Sciences program. The emphasis of the program is beginning to shift towards biological research. Hanson surveys University of Iowa, Cornell, Jackson Memorial Laboratory and the University of Virginia. He attends a meeting of drosophila workers.
    Diaries; United States; Botany; Zoology; Biology -- Research; Chemistry; Physics; Rockefeller Foundation; Hanson, Frank B.
  - 1934 January 8-April 30 (Box 192, Reel M Han 1, Frame 518)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Hanson, professionals and students in the field of natural sciences. Entries record his tours of various laboratories, discussions of research and impressions of fellowship applicants. He tours various universities in the United States and Canada to survey their current research. Hanson attends a symposium on heavy water.
    Physics; Botany; Zoology; Biology -- Research; Diaries; Chemistry; Canada; United States; Rockefeller Foundation; Hanson, Frank B.
  - 1934 May 1-December 31 (Box 192, Reel M Han 1, Frame 652)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Hanson, professionals and students in the field of natural sciences. Entries record his tours of various laboratories, discussions of research and impressions of fellowship applicants. He tours various universities in the United States to survey their current research. Hanson attends the Summer Meeting of the Genetics Society of America at Woods Hole and the AAAS Pittsburgh Meeting.
    Zoology; Biology -- Research; Chemistry; United States; Botany; Diaries; Physics; Rockefeller Foundation; Hanson, Frank B.
  - 1935 January 4-June 28 (Box 192, Reel M Han 1, Frame 811)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Hanson, professionals and students in the field of natural sciences. Entries record his tours of various laboratories, discussions of research and impressions of fellowship applicants. He tours various universities in the United States to survey their current research. The present program of the division of natural sciences of the RF aims to assist in the understanding of behavior. The focus of the program is moving towards experimental biology. Programs from previous years are still open and active.
    Biology -- Research; Zoology; United States; Chemistry; Botany; Physics; Diaries; Rockefeller Foundation; Hanson, Frank B.
  - 1935 July 3-December 23 (Box 192, Reel M Han 1, Frame 908)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Hanson, professionals and students in the field of natural sciences. Entries record his tours of various laboratories, discussions of research and impressions of fellowship applicants. He tours various universities in the United States to survey their current research. The present program of the division of natural sciences of the RF aims to assist in the understanding of behavior. The focus of the program is moving towards experimental biology. Programs from previous years are still open and active. Hanson attends a spectroscopic conference and surveys Woods Hole a former program investing in oceanographic work at sea.
    Diaries; United States; Chemistry; Oceanography; Zoology; Biology -- Research; Physics; Botany; Rockefeller Foundation; Hanson, Frank B.
  - 1936 January 1-April 30 (Box 192, Reel M Han 2, Frame 24)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Hanson, professionals and students in the field of natural sciences. Entries records his tours of various laboratories, discussions of research and impressions of fellowship applicants. He tours various universities in the United States to survey their current research. The present program of the division of natural sciences of the RF aims to assist in the understanding of behavior. The focus of the program is moving towards experimental biology. Hanson attends an AAAS meeting and the Meeting of the American Association of Anatomists.
    Diaries; Endocrinology; Mathematics; Physics; Physiology; Genetics; Chemistry; Zoology; Biology -- Research; Rockefeller Foundation; Hanson, Frank B.
  - 1936 May 4-December 31 (Box 193, Reel M Han 2, Frame 152)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Hanson, professionals and students in the field of natural sciences. Entries record his tours of various laboratories, discussions of research and impressions of fellowship applicants. He tours various universities in the United States to survey their current research. The present program of the division of natural sciences of the RF aims to assist in the understanding of behavior. The focus of the program is moving towards experimental biology. Hanson attends an AAAS meeting and the Meeting of the American Association of Anatomists.